- I have AI conversations all the time.
-我一直在進行 AI 對話。
At the dinner table, at the grocery store.
在餐桌上，在雜貨店。
I'm only slightly exaggerating.
我只是稍微放大。
It feels like everyone is talking about AI.
感覺像每個人都在談論 AI。
You might feel like you need to become an expert overnight.
您可能會覺得需要一夜成為專家。
But what if I told you that using AI effectively
但是，如果我告訴你
has less to do with being a tech genius,
有效的使用 AI 不與成為一個技術天才有關，
and more to do with understanding a few simple principles.
而更與了解一些簡單的原則有關。
Let's start with some of the things AI can do
讓我們從 AI 可以做的一些事情以
and how it can help you at work.
及它如何在工作中為您提供幫助。
First, AI can help you understand information.
首先，AI 可以幫助您了解信息。
Think of summarizing multi-page reports in seconds,
想想在幾秒鐘內總結多頁報告，
getting insights from a dense spreadsheet,
從密集的試算表中獲得見解
or getting up to speed on a client's industry.
，或了解客戶的產業。
This can help set you up for better decisions.
這可以幫助您做出更好的決策。
AI can also create new things.
AI 也可以創造新事物。
It can help you draft communications,
它可以幫助您草擬通訊、
build the outline of a presentation,
構建簡報的大綱，
and even generate product images.
甚至產生產品圖像。
And finally, AI can help you improve your work.
最後，AI 可以幫助您改善工作。
It can poke holes in a project plan,
它可以在項目計劃中突破洞，
or suggest ways to make a client proposal better,
或提出改善客戶提案的方法，
and it can give you fresh ideas for you to evaluate.
並且可以為您提供新的想法供您評估。
My team uses AI all the time.
我的團隊一直使用 AI。
Our job is to create efficiencies
我們的工作是提高效率
and drive for impact for Google research.
並為 Google 研究帶來影響力。
I'm always inspired by the ideas they come up with
我總是受到他們在日常工作中
for using AI in our everyday work.
使用 AI 的想法所提出的啟發。
So how do you get AI to work for you?
那麼，您如何讓 AI 為您工作？
Good news is if you can give instructions,
好消息是，如果你能給出指示
you already have some of the skills.
，你已經擁有一些技能。
That's because AI understands natural language.
這是因為 AI 理解自然語言。
That means you communicate through everyday words,
這意味著您通過日常單詞進行交流，
either through typing or through speech.
無論是通過打字或通過語音。
But if you wanna go
但是，如果你想
from being a good user to a really effective user,
從一個好用戶轉為一個真正有效的用戶，
there's some technique involved.
那麼需要一些技術。
Let's talk about some of the things you need to know.
讓我們談談一些你需要知道的事情。
The key to using AI well
善用 AI 的關鍵在
is giving clear and specific instructions, or prompts.
於提供清晰而具體的指示或提示。
Prompts are instructions you give to AI
提示是您向 AI 提供的指示
to get the results that you want.
，以獲得所需的結果。
Sometimes you'll upload files
有時，您會在
or other documents in your prompt
提示中上傳要求的文件或其他文檔
that you want it to take into account.
，這些文件都要考慮。
Everything you include in your prompt is called an input.
您在提示中包含的所有內容都稱為輸入。
What AI generates in return is called the output.
AI 回報產生的東西稱為輸出。
Knowing how to prompt well
知道如何良好提示
is a fundamental skill to unlock AI's full capabilities.
是解鎖 AI 全部功能的基本技能。
Because AI is frequently changing,
由於 AI 經常發生變化，
you might hear about new features, apps,
因此您可能會聽到發布新功能、應用程
and models being released.
式和模型。
It can feel like a lot to keep track of.
感覺很多可以跟踪。
So let's break down what these terms mean
因此，讓我們分解這些術語的意義
so you'll know how to leverage these advancements at work.
，以便您知道如何在工作中利用這些進步。
First, let's start with the AI model Gemini.
首先，讓我們從 AI 模型 Gemini 開始。
Think of the model as a car's engine under the hood.
將車型視為引擎蓋下的汽車引擎。
It's the technology
這是
that does the actual reasoning and generation.
實際推理和生成的技術。
Even though the engine provides all the horsepower,
即使發動機提供所有馬力
you don't need to interact with it directly.
，但您不需要直接與其互動。
So to make use of the engine, what would you do?
那麼要利用引擎，你會做什麼？
Well, as the driver, you get into the car.
好吧，身為司機，你上車。
That car is the AI app, and you're in the driver's seat.
那輛車是 AI 應用程序，您就坐在駕駛座位。
In this course, our home base will be the Gemini app.
在本課程中，我們的主基地將是 Gemini 應用程序。
You can access it on your phone
您可以在手機上
or via the web at gemini.google.com.
或通過 gemini.google.com 網絡訪問它。
Okay, you're in the car.
好吧，你在車上
Now how do you get it to do what you want?
現在你怎麼讓它做到你想要的事情？
You press the ignition button, grab the steering wheel,
你按點火按鈕抓起方向盤
and push that gas pedal, right?
然後按油踏板，對吧？
Well, to command AI, we use parts of its interface,
好吧，要命令 AI，我們使用其界面的部分
like the chat box and its features.
，例如聊天框和其功能。
When a new feature's released,
新功能發布後，
you can go back to the app and check it out.
您可以返回應用程序並查看它。
But the Gemini models power more than just the Gemini app.
但雙子座模型不僅僅僅是 Gemini 應用程序的功能。
It's a family of some of Google's most capable AI models,
它是一些 Google 最有能力的 AI 模型的一系
and it's built into products like Google search,
列，它內置在 Google 搜索、
Maps, Pixel, and more.
地圖、Pixel 等產品中。
While you're in the Gemini app,
當您使用 Gemini 應用程序時，
you can explore different models and features
您可以探索不同的模型和功能
to pick the right one for what you're trying to accomplish.
，以為您嘗試實現的選擇合適的模型和功能。
So what's the best model for your task?
那麼，什麼是您任務的最佳模型？
Different AI models have different strengths,
不同的 AI 模型具有不同的優勢
depending on how they were trained
，具體取決於他們的訓
and how their learning was refined.
練方式和學習的精進方式。
Some models are really good
有些型號非常
at quickly providing all-around help.
擅長快速提供全方位幫助。
Other models might be best for advanced tasks
其他模型可能最適合進階
like research, coding,
任務，例如研究、編
or weighing the pros and cons of a complicated decision.
碼或衡量複雜決策的優缺點。
Keep in mind, more complex tasks require more computations,
請記住，更複雜的任務需要更多的計算，模型
which could take the model longer to complete.
可能需要更長時間才能完成。
As you use different AI tools,
當您使用不同的 AI 工具
there are other things you can do
時，您可以做其他操作
to customize your experience.
來自定義體驗。
For example, Google AI Studio offers advanced settings
例如，Google AI Studio 提供高級設置，
such as temperature, but temperature in this context
例如溫度，但在這種情況下，溫度
isn't about whether or not you need a jacket,
不是關於您是否需要外套，而
it's about controlling the creativity in AI's output.
是關於控制 AI 輸出中的創造力。
A lower temperature setting means the output
較低的溫度設置意味著輸
will likely be more predictable and consistent.
出可能更可預測和一致。
A higher temperature
更高的溫度意
means you'll get a more inventive output
味著您將獲得更具創意性的輸出，而
that could be less predictable.
且可能不容易預測。
Remember, AI doesn't know anything, it's just using its data
請記住，AI 什麼都不知道，它只是使用其數據
and learning to predict what the best answer might be
並學習從一系列可能的
from a range of possible options.
選項中預測最佳答案可能是什麼。
Temperature is just one way to experiment with this.
溫度只是實驗這種方法的一種。
Okay, it's time to start putting this into practice.
好吧，是時候開始實踐這個了。